I, uh, I keep having this dream.
Where I see that guy from the
mountains who hung himself.
He must've been planning to do it,
so why did he tell us his story first?
Couldn't say.
Doubt we'll ever know.
He was probably hoping
that we'd forgive him,
but after the way we abandoned Marcel,
we were in no position to.
I don't know if it
was forgiveness he was after.
I couldn't really
tell you why, but I think
he just wanted to be judged.
Evening. It's been
four years, Reiner.
Hey, uh... What's wrong?
Mr. Kruger said
you were old friends
and that he wanted to surprise you.
It's true, right?
You two were friends?
Yeah. And we have
a whole lot to catch up on.
I don't even know where to start.
It can't be.
Eren.
Lord Tybur. It's almost time.
Thank you.
My goodness!
Well, well! Lady Azumabito.
Come to give me a pep talk?
I'm sorry to interrupt your preparations.
I just wanted to see your face.
It must be a haunting sight.
I seem to have a
bad case of stage-fright.
Fear not. You look
courageous and dignified.
You are a truly brave man.
My family knows that well.
I'll wish you luck and take my leave.
I'm glad you came by.
Thanks, Kiyomi.
Sit down, Reiner.
I found us good seats.
You can hear everything
that happens on stage.
We're right beneath
an apartment building.
It's behind the stage, but still.
It's full of excited families
waiting at their windows
for the curtains to rise.
They're all directly above us.
Say, Mister Kruger.
Did you cut your hand?
Yeah. It's just a scratch.
Reiner. Sit.
So, uh, I think I should
head back to the others now.
No, Falco.
You should stay here and listen to us.
Huh?
Just... do as
he says, all right?
'Kay.
Now then. Let's get out of here.
Hello. It's been quite
a while, Mr. Leonhart.
Evening, Ms. Braun.
I don't believe I've seen you
since your son came home.
Speaking of which,
I hear Mr. Hoover died.
In his sleep, I believe.
He did. He always
used to speak of
how proud he was of his son's courage.
How he gave his all for Marley.
I'm sure that Annie was just as brave...
She's not dead.
My daughter is alive.
One day she'll come back.
She promised me she would.
To think.
We're about to declare war on
what's left of Eldia from
the Eldian Internment Zone.
Wow. Even General Calvi's here!
Along with almost every other
important Marleyan officer.
The crowd's also full of
nobles and ambassadors.
Not to mention
journalists from every newspaper
in the world that's worth the ink.
It kinda feels like we're the
center of the world, doesn't it?
The Tyburs did this?
Can't believe they're this powerful.
Even though they're
just as Eldian as we are.
I guess it's starting.
Falco and Mr. Braun
haven't come back yet.
Commander Magath sent me.
He needs his Eldian Warriors.
Why, Eren...
Why come here?
What do you plan to do?
The exact same thing you did.
No. I...
As for why.
That's the same, too.
I don't have a choice.
That's why.
Sounds like the show's begun.
We should listen.
Let's pull back the veil of time.
Roughly a century ago, the
Eldian Empire ruled the world
through the might of its Titans.
Humanity as we know it
could go extinct three times over,
and the body count still wouldn't match
the number of lives
that Titans have stolen.
Such is the legacy of the founder, Ymir.
So much has been lost.
Countless peoples
and cultures, wiped out.
Histories crushed
underfoot with their pride.
Eldia's history is all we have left.
And it tells only of killing.
You see, once the Eldians
ran out of foes to conquer,
they began to fight amongst
themselves, vying for power.
Thus began the Great Titan War,
which saw eight of the Nine Titans
locked in an endless cycle of bloodshed.
But there was one brilliant Marleyan
who saw in this chaos, a path to victory.
He was the heroic paragon
we all know as Helos.
Thanks to his cunning manipulations,
Eldian infighting grew far
worse, and the Empire grew weak.
Then, Helos joined hands
with the Tybur family,
and they forced the supposedly
unbeatable King Fritz
to retreat to a far-flung island.
That said, he fled
with his powers intact,
and his reign continued.
With him, he took tens
of millions of Titans,
ready to trample the
world at his command.
It's believed that our world
continues to exist unbroken
for one reason alone.
Chance.
Our scholars can field
no better explanation.
In order to fight
this existential threat,
my motherland, Marley, sent a
team of four Titan Warriors
to take the Founder.
But they were soundly beaten,
and only the Armored Titan returned.
It's clear now.
The ancient engine of cruelty
called the Eldian Empire
is alive and well today.
Honestly, it makes sense.
I get why you plunged my home into hell.
You were on a mission
to save the world, right?
So you had to.
My orders are to send
you to the gate, Jaeger.
All right.
This way, you two.
I feel like I've seen you before,
but I can't quite place you.
Where are you stationed?
My unit's out west, near Lakua.
They sent me to help bolster security.
I'm not interested in
chatting with an Eldian,
even if you are a Warrior.
Well isn't that a shame?
I'd started to take a real
liking to your beard.
Oh!
Pieck!
It's the Panzer Unit!
Thanks for all your hard work, guys!
Oh, uh, honestly,
we should be thanking you.
You're in a really good mood today.
What are you doing? Let's go.
What was that?
What? Those soldiers ride
the Cart Titan into battle.
I need their support, so I try
to build a bond with them.
Well, no offense, but it seems
like ya did more harm than good.
Hear anything?
Nothing yet, sir.
Everything's quiet for now.
Report everything you hear to me.
I don't care how
insignificant it may seem.
Yes, sir.
In here. Go.
So, where's Commander Magath?
Porco!
Okay. What's going on here?
Why does Vice Chief Braun seem so afraid?
Mr. Kruger said they
were old friends, but...
Old friends?
Just how many years has he known him?
If it's more than four, then...
they met on Paradis.
Wait. That can't be right.
Because... if it is...
It can't be.
Oh no.
The history I just recounted
to be common knowledge,
but I stand here now
to inform you that it is
somewhat divorced from truth.
I know this because the War Hammer
isn't the only inheritance
the Tybur family bestows.
We've passed down memories as well.
Truths which I will now share with you.
He's going off-script.
Not sure why.
...the Great
Titan War was ended,
not by Helos, nor by my Tybur forebears.
The savior who ended the fighting,
the hero who saved the world,
was King Fritz himself.
He was plagued by guilt
over the Eldian Empire's vicious past.
He'd grown weary of watching
families and countrymen
torn apart by war,
and he wept for Marley, a nation
under constant oppression.
So when he inherited the Founding Titan,
he plotted his own
downfall with the Tyburs.
Together, we created
a Marleyan hero who would
drive the king out.
His name: Helos.
After that, King Fritz moved
as many Eldians to Paradis as he could,
erecting his great walls around them.
He left a warning.
That if anyone threatened his peace,
countless Titans would be
unleashed in retaliation.
However, he never intended
to make good on this threat.
King Fritz made a vow renouncing war,
and bound his successors
to uphold it just as he had.
Thus, his ideology was passed down
to each new King of the Walls,
and the Titans with the
power to crush the world
remained dormant.
Marley didn't stop Eldia,
and chance hasn't kept
the world from being crushed.
It was the King of the Walls, Karl Fritz.
A man who yearned for peace.
That's it. That's all he wanted.
He said that if Marley
grew strong someday,
and came in force to shatter his peace
and seize the Founding Titan,
he would accept it.
He believed the sins his people
committed were so horrific
that they could never be atoned for.
"When the day of
retribution finally comes,
I will accept it, but until then,
let me enjoy this walled
paradise, free from strife.
I ask for nothing but
a brief span of peace."
Those were the final words
the King left us with.
What does this mean?
If what he's saying is true...
So Marley and the Tybur family
didn't really save the world?
Well, General? Your thoughts?
But if the King of the Walls...
Willy wouldn't lie.
...that
means Paradis doesn't actually
pose a threat, right?
It's true. To secure
our own safety,
my family joined hands with King Fritz.
We became heroes to the world,
while our fellow Eldians became devils.
Put plainly, we Tyburs are petty thieves,
growing fat on honor we did not earn.
I stand before you, willingly
parting with my false glory.
Because I have come to understand
that the world we share
is in grave danger.
Commander!
The Warriors are gone,
and we haven't heard from
any of the soldiers
we sent to collect them.
Mobilize the reserves at once.
Track them down!
Yes, sir!
Looks like it's begun.
Shit. That really hurt.
What the hell is this place?
Looks like a pit meant
to detain Warriors like us.
It's a classic.
The space is too cramped to transform in,
and with two of us down here...
Hmm, got it.
We'd just crush each other.
I'm still confused though.
What's that soldier's plan?
Couldn't tell you.
They really were familiar,
though. I know that much.
Please stay and watch.
This is my atonement.
With the Founder's might,
King Fritz erected three walls,
using a great host of Colossal Titans.
Counted together,
the walls surely contain
tens of millions of Colossal Titans.
They guard the king's peace
as his shield and his spear.
Or they did, but now that peace
is being threatened from within.
An uprising has taken place on Paradis.
The King has been deposed.
The Founding Titan: Stolen.
The thief is an enemy to
every man, woman, and child
outside of his island.
An enemy of peace.
His name... is Eren Jaeger!
You tricked me.
After what you said, I respected you.
But you were just using me.
Yeah, I was. I'm sorry.
I did it 'cause I needed your help.
The letters you had me send
from outside the internment zone.
Who were they to?
I can't say the letters
made it to my family, but
they reached my comrades.
But I... I didn't know.
Wait. You wrote your comrades?
If the Colossi of
Paradis are ordered to walk,
the rumbling will be
felt across the earth,
and death will follow.
Until now, only royalty has had the power
to wield the Founding Titan,
and King Fritz' vow has kept
his descendants from using it.
But this Eren Jaeger
has found a way to use
the Founder without having royal blood.
Which means he could begin
the rumbling at any moment.
Once the walls of Paradis begin to walk,
there will be nothing we can do
except flee in vain from
the sound of earthshaking steps
that will herald our doom.
These monsters will crush every city,
trample every tree and flower.
They will literally flatten our world.
He's exactly right.
I'm the bad guy Willy says I am.
If nobody stops me,
there's a chance that
I'll destroy your whole world.
But to my eyes, you looked
like the bad guys, too.
That day, when you breached the wall.
When Titans destroyed my home.
When I watched as my mom was eaten.
I couldn't
understand it. Why, Reiner?
Tell me why my mom was eaten by a Titan.
It's because we broke the wall
that was protecting her.
Why did you break the wall?
So we could use the chaos to sneak in,
and to find out if the king would react.
But what was your mission?
To save the world by taking the Founder.
Well that's that.
If all that was to save the world, then
you didn't have much choice.
I remember what you said.
You promised we'd pay for what
we did and you promised pain.
So are you here to make me pay?
Yeah. I did say that, didn't I?
Huh?
Let's forget about that.
At first, I considered every person
on this side of the sea an enemy.
But later, I crossed the sea
and slept under my enemy's roof.
Ate the food they offered me.
Reiner. I'm the same as you.
Some of these people are awful.
But some are good.
Same where I'm from.
Inside the walls, we're all just people.
But you were taught that
the people in the walls
weren't like you, that we were demons.
You were just kids who got brainwashed.
Hatred was part of your training.
As young as you were,
how could you have fought that?
You couldn't have, and well it...
It looks like you've already paid.
No! You're wrong, Eren!
That day...
When the Titan got Marcel,
Annie and Bertholdt wanted to
end the mission right then.
And they would've.
But I convinced them to keep going.
Not just to save my own skin, but...
Because I wanted to become a hero!
I wanted to be respected.
It's my fault!
The... The truth is your
mother was eaten by a Titan
because of me!
I have always hated my blood.
And more than anyone,
I have wished that
my race would disappear.
I can't take this anymore.
Please. Just kill me.
However, I confess that I want to live.
That despite everything,
I believe this world is my
birthright, just as it is yours.
The people gathered here
may belong to different races,
different nations, but if
we're to survive this crisis
then for the first time in
history, we must join as one.
So please.
If you wish to live,
then lend me your strength.
Help me protect our world's future!
If we work together,
we can overcome any obstacle.
Any threat!
I was right.
I am the same as you.
Huh?
I ask each of you to join me
as I go to fight the devils
who would plunge our world into hell.
Help me defeat them!
I think maybe we were born this way.
Here and now,
as a representative of
Marley's government,
I send this message
to the devils of Paradis.
I'll just keep moving forward.
Huh...?
Till I've killed my enemies.
Consider this
a declaration of war!
The Attack Titan appears out of nowhere,
roaring like a demon as it kills
enemies and innocents alike.
To stop Eren's rampage,
the War Hammer swings.
Next episode:
"The War Hammer Titan."